Register of the Charles Easton Rothwell papers, 1924-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- Stanford University and Hoover Institution, 1932-1988 (Box 22-27)
  - Subject file
    - Travel
      - Brochures (Box-folder 27: 11)
      - Contact-notebook (Box-folder 27: 12)
      - Correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 13)
      - Train schedule (Box-folder 27: 14)
      - Trips
        - Washington - New York
          - 1946 June 26 - 1947 July 8 (Box-folder 27: 15)
          - 1947 August 13 - 1947 September 4 (Box-folder 27: 16)
        - Washington, D.C., 1948 February 9-16 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 27: 19)
- Mills College, 1957-1969 (Box 28-35)
  Brochures, bulletins, commencement records, correspondence, curriculum, financial records, list of alumnae clubs, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletters, pamphlets, printed matter, reports, speeches, statements, and telegrams relating to Charles Rothwell's years at Mills College as its eighth President, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Also includes the records of the involvement of Mills College in the community (the city of Oakland) under his leadership; his presidential household inventory and gift items; cultural events at Mills College during his tenure; the elaborate selection process by which the presidential selection committee selected Charles Rothwell as the President; his trips across the United States to visit the alumnae clubs; and above all, the dedication of Rothwell College Center as a tribute to the Rothwells for their significant contribution to the development of Mills College as a leading educational institution for women in the United States.
  - General (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Brochures (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Bulletins (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 28: 4-5)
  - Commencement records (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Committee records
    - Committee on Admissions and Students' Aid (Box-folder 29: 2)
    - Committee on Education Policies (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - Undated (Box-folder 29: 4)
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 29: 5)
      - 1958
        - January-December 22 (Box-folder 29: 6)
        - December 23-30 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      - 1959
        - January 1-10 (Box-folder 29: 8)
        - January 12-31 (Box-folder 29: 9)
        - February (Box-folder 29: 10)
        - March (Box-folder 29: 11)
        - September-December (Box-folder 29: 12)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 29: 13)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 29: 14)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 29: 15)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 29: 16)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 29: 17)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 29: 18)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - 1969-1974 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Athenian School (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Commission on Liberal Education (Box-folder 30: 5)
    - University of Denver, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 30: 6-10)
  - Description of curriculum (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Directory (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Donations (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Financial records (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Handbook (Box-folder 30: 15)
  - List of alumnae clubs (Box-folder 30: 16)
  - List of books (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Memoranda, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Newsletters (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Organizational records
    - Academic (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - Associate Council (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Board of Trustees and Regional Trustees (Box-folder 31: 7-8)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 31: 10-11)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - Profile of Mills College (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Programs (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Proposal (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Reports
    - 1957 (Box-folder 31: 16)
    - 1959-1969 (Box-folder 32: 1-4)
  - Schedule (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Speeches, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Statements, 1957 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Subject file
    - Association of American Colleges, Pugwash Conference Pugwash, Nova Scotia (Box-folder 32: 8)
    - City of Oakland
      - Freeway
        - Clippings (Box-folder 32: 9)
        - Comic strips (Box-folder 33: 10)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 32: 11)
      - Museum
        - General (Box-folder 32: 12)
        - Clippings (Box-folder 32: 13)
        - Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 32: 14)
        - Minutes of meetings, 1962 (Box-folder 32: 15)
        - Program (Box-folder 32: 16)
      - Space, Science, and Urban Life Conference and October Workshop
        - General (Box-folder 32: 17)
        - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 32: 18)
        - Memoranda, 1962 (Box-folder 32: 19)
        - Minutes of meetings, 1962 (Box-folder 32: 20)
        - Newsletters (Box-folder 32: 21)
        - Notes (Box-folder 32: 22)
        - Printed matter (Box-folder 32: 23)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 32: 24)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 32: 25)
    - College Affairs Assembly (Box-folder 33: 1-11)
    - College Founders Day, 1965
      - General (Box-folder 33: 12)
      - Brochures (Box-folder 33: 13)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 33: 14)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 33: 15)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 33: 16)
      - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 33: 17)
      - Program (Box-folder 33: 18)
      - Schedule (Box-folder 33: 19)
      - Seating chart (Box-folder 33: 20)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 33: 21)
    - College President's household
      - Financial records (Box-folder 33: 22)
      - Gifts and the inventory of items in President's house (Box-folder 33: 23)
    - Cultural, musical and social events
      - Cultural events (Box-folder 33: 24)
      - Musical events
        - 1961 (Box-folder 33: 25)
        - Milhaud Festival, 1963 (Box-folder 33: 26)
      - Social events
        - General (Box-folder 33: 27)
        - 1957-1960 (Box-folder 33: 28)
        - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 33: 29)
        - 1963 (Box-folder 33: 30)
        - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 34: 1)
        - 1966-1971 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - Inauguration of Charles Easton Rothwell as President (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Presidential Selection Committee, 1958
      - General (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 34: 6)
      - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - Reports (Box-folder 34: 8)
    - Rothwell College Center dedication, tribute to the Rothwells, 1967
      - General (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 34: 10)
      - Invitations
        - Acceptances (Box-folder 34: 11)
        - Regrets (Box-folder 34: 12)
        - Thank you letters (Box-folder 34: 13)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 34: 14)
      - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 34: 15)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 34: 16)
      - Schedule and assignments (Box-folder 34: 17)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 34: 18)
  - Symposium proceedings (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Tributes (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Trip records
    - General (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - Chicago, Illinois, 19??, May 9 (Box-folder 35: 5)
    - 1959
      - Eastern states, June 14-July 12
        - Financial records (Box-folder 35: 6)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 35: 7)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 35: 8)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 35: 9)
      - Portland, Oregon, August 1 (Box-folder 35: 10)
      - Santa Barbara, California, October 24-25 (Box-folder 35: 11)
      - Denver, Colorado, November 5-6
        - General (Box-folder 35: 12)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 13)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 35: 14)
      - Omaha, Nebraska, November 7
        - General (Box-folder 35: 15)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 16)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 35: 17)
        - Reservation slip (Box-folder 35: 18)
      - Midwest and Eastern states, November 8-10
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 19)
        - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 20)
      - Chicago, Illinois, November 8-9
        - General (Box-folder 35: 21)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 22)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 35: 23)
        - Newsletters (Box-folder 35: 24)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 35: 25)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 35: 26)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 35: 27)
    - Eastern and Northwestern states, 1960 January-February
      - General (Box-folder 35: 28)
      - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 29)
    - 1961
      - St. Louis, Missouri, January 18
        - General (Box-folder 35: 30)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 31)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 35: 32)
      - Oklahoma, January 19-21
        - General (Box-folder 35: 33)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 34)
        - Notes (Box-folder 35: 35)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 35: 36)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 35: 37)
    - Southern California, 1962 January 16-24
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 38)
      - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 39)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 35: 40)
    - 1963
      - Chicago, Illinois, February 3-5
        - General (Box-folder 35: 41)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 42)
        - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 43)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 35: 44)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 35: 45)
      - Far East, March-April
        - General (Box-folder 35: 46)
        - Clippings (Box-folder 35: 47)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 48)
        - Notes (Box-folder 35: 49)
        - Printed matter (Box-folder 35: 50)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 35: 51)
      - Spokane, Washington, September 8-16
        - General (Box-folder 35: 52)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 35: 53)
        - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 54)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 35: 55)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 35: 56)
- National War College, 1949-1980 (Box 35-38)
  Brochure, correspondence, conference proceedings, courses of instruction, library records, memoranda, notes, pamphlets, printed matter, reports, research papers, and telegrams relating to Charles Rothwell's years of association with the National War College as a staff member and as a member of the Board of Consultants, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Committee assignments (Box-folder 35: 57)
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 35: 58)
    - A-C (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - D-H (Box-folder 36: 2)
    - J-R (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - S-Z (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Conference proceedings (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Curriculum (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Directory (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Itinerary of Charles Easton Rothwell (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - Library records (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Memoranda, 1951 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - Notes (Box-folder 36: 11)
  - Organization and functions, charts (Box-folder 36: 12)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - Research projects (Box-folder 37: 3-4)
  - Remarks, 1949-1959 (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - Reports, 1951 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Research papers (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Subject file, courses of instruction
    - General
      - General (Box-folder 37: 8)
      - Report on courses (Box-folder 37: 9)
      - Roster of the class (Box-folder 37: 10)
      - Course I - Basic Strategic Considerations in the Formulation of United States National Policy (Box-folder 37: 11)
      - Course II - Economics (Box-folder 37: 12)
      - Course III - International Politics (Box-folder 37: 13)
      - Course IV - U. S. Government and Foreign Policy Formulation (Box-folder 37: 14)
      - Course V - The U.S.S.R (Box-folder 37: 15)
      - Course VI - Western Continental Europe (Box-folder 38: 1)
      - Course VII - British Commomwealth of Nations (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - Course VIII - Latin America (Box-folder 38: 3)
      - Course IX and X - Near East, Middle East, and East (Box-folder 38: 4)
      - Course XI - The Far East (Box-folder 38: 5)
      - Course XII - United States Foreign Policy (Box-folder 38: 6)
      - Course XIII - Military Strategy (Box-folder 38: 7)
      - Course XV - Political, Economic and Psychological Warfare (Box-folder 38: 8)
      - Course XXIII - Individual Strategic Studies (Box-folder 38: 9)
    - Individual Study Courses (Box-folder 38: 10)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 38: 11)
- United Nations and State Department, 1943-1987 (Box 38-55)
  Articles, basic reference book, brochures, bulletins, chronology of events, committees, correspondence, fact sheets, list of delegates to the United Nations conference, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletters, preamble to the Charter, press comments, printed matter, remarks, reports, records relating to the site selection process, telegrams, workbooks, writings, and working papers relating to the Dumbarton Oaks, San Francisco, and other conferences and United Nations anniversary celebrations in subsequent years, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: Incremental Materials and Declassified U.S. Government Records series.
  - General (Box-folder 38: 12)
  - Articles (Box-folder 38: 13)
  - Analysis of editorial opinion (Box-folder 38: 14)
  - Background information (Box-folder 38: 15)
  - Basic reference book (Box-folder 38: 16)
  - Biographical information (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Brochures (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Bulletins (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Check list for attendance and votes (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Chronology of United Nations cooperation (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 39: 6-8)
  - Commemoration records of the signing of the United Nations Charter (Box-folder 39: 9-11)
  - Commemoration records of the signing of the United Nations Charter (Box-folder 40: 1-6)
  - Comments and proposed amendments concerning the Dumbarton Oaks Proposals
    - General (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - "Commentaires Des Propositions De Dumbarton Oaks Et Projets D'Amendements" (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - "Comentarios Sobre Las Propuestas De Dumbarton Oakes Y Proyectos De Emmiendas" (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Committees and Commission records
    - General (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - Atomic Energy Commission (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - Committee IV/1 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - Committee of Experts (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Coordination Committee (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - Fifth Committee (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Military Staff Committee (Box-folder 42: 4-5)
    - Preparatory Commission (Box-folder 42: 6)
    - Steering Committee (Box-folder 42: 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - 1944 May-December (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - 1945
      - April-May (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - June-August (Box-folder 43: 4)
        Includes some letters to Edward R. Stettinius. See also: Correspondence series.
    - 1946 March-September (Box-folder 43: 5)
    - 1947 April-December (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - 1948
      - January-May (Box-folder 43: 7)
      - June-November (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - 1949
      - February-May (Box-folder 43: 9)
      - June-December (Box-folder 43: 10)
    - 1951-1987 (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - Daily summary cables (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Delegates to the United Nations Conference list (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Documents
    - General (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Distribution list (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Dumbarton Oaks documents on international organization (Box-folder 44: 5-6)
    - Samples of documentation (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - Facsimile of the Charter of the United Nations (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Fact sheets (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - Final Charter production instructions (Box-folder 45: 3-4)
  - Financial records (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - Floor plan (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - Guide (Box-folder 45: 7)
  - Information copy (Box-folder 45: 8)
  - Inventory of archives (Box-folder 45: 9)
  - Invitations (Box-folder 45: 10)
  - Journal (Box-folder 45: 11)
  - Language issue (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - Leaflets (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - List of consultants and associates (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - List of guest passes (Box-folder 46: 4)
  - List of participants at Dumbarton Oaks (Box-folder 46: 5)
  - List of publications about the United Nations (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - Map (Box-folder 46: 7)
    See also: Declassified U.S. Government Records, 2016 January release of records.
  - Manifesto (Box-folder 46: 8)
  - Memoranda
    - General
      - 1943 August (Box-folder 46: 9)
      - 1944 August (Box-folder 46: 10)
      - 1945
        - March-April (Box-folder 46: 11)
        - May (Box-folder 46: 12)
        - June (Box-folder 46: 13)
        - July-December (Box-folder 46: 14)
      - 1946 June-September (Box-folder 46: 15)
      - 1947 February (Box-folder 46: 16)
      - 1948 March-April (Box-folder 46: 17)
      - 1949 April-May (Box-folder 46: 18)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 46: 19)
    - Washington conversations on international organization - Dumbarton Oaks, 1944 (Box-folder 46: 20)
  - Message (Box-folder 46: 21)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - Undated (Box-folder 46: 22)
    - General (Box-folder 46: 23)
    - 1944 December (Box-folder 46: 24)
    - 1945
      - April (Box-folder 46: 25)
      - May (Box-folder 47: 1)
      - June (Box-folder 47: 2)
  - Newsletters (Box-folder 47: 3)
  - News digest (Box-folder 47: 4)
  - Notes (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Personnel file (Box-folder 47: 7-8)
  - Plans of international organization (Box-folder 47: 9)
  - Plenary session (Box-folder 47: 10)
  - Preamble to the United Nations Charter (Box-folder 47: 11)
  - Press comments and summary (Box-folder 47: 12)
  - Press comments and summary (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 48: 2)
  - Pictorial record (Box-folder 48: 3)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 48: 4-5)
  - Procedure (Box-folder 49: 1-2)
  - Program (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - Projects (Box-folder 49: 4)
  - Proposal (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Outline (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - Radio comments (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - Recommendations (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - Regional organizations and arrangements file (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - Remarks, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 49: 10)
  - Reports
    - Undated (Box-folder 49: 11)
    - 1943 November (Box-folder 49: 12)
    - 1945
      - April (Box-folder 49: 13)
      - June-December (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - 1954 April - 1958 August (Box-folder 50: 3)
  - Resolutions presented by delegates (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Roundtable discussion transcripts (Box-folder 50: 5)
  - Schedule (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Site selection records (Box-folder 50: 7)
  - Statements, 1944 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - Statistical summary (Box-folder 50: 9)
  - Study (Box-folder 50: 10)
  - Subject file
    - American Association for the United Nations, Inc.
      - General (Box-folder 50: 11)
      - Correspondence, 1947 September - 1954 June (Box-folder 51: 1)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 51: 2)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1948 July - 1949 November (Box-folder 51: 3)
      - Notes (Box-folder 51: 4)
      - Press release (Box-folder 51: 5)
      - Printed matter (Box-folder 51: 6)
      - Program (Box-folder 51: 7)
      - Proposal (Box-folder 51: 8)
      - Reports, 1948 (Box-folder 51: 9)
      - Statements, 1949 (Box-folder 51: 10)
      - Telegrams (Box-folder 51: 11)
      - Television news report, 1949 April (Box-folder 51: 12)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 51: 13)
    - General International Organization
      - General (Box-folder 51: 14-15)
      - Charts (Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish) (Box-folder 51: 16)
      - Economic and Social Council (Box-folder 51: 17)
      - General Assembly (Box-folder 51: 18)
      - Security Council (Box-folder 51: 19)
      - Security Council (Box-folder 52: 1-3)
      - World Health Organization (WHO) (Box-folder 52: 4)
      - Workbook (Box-folder 52: 5-6)
    - Pacific Regional Conference on UNESCO (United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization)
      - General (Box-folder 52: 7)
      - Background information (Box-folder 52: 8)
      - Brochure (Box-folder 52: 9)
      - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 52: 10)
      - Memoranda, 1948 January-June (Box-folder 52: 11)
      - Minutes of meetings
        - General (Box-folder 53: 1)
        - 1948 March-May (Box-folder 53: 2)
      - Outline (Box-folder 53: 3)
      - Press releases (Box-folder 53: 4)
      - Program (Box-folder 53: 5)
      - Reports, 1948 (Box-folder 53: 6)
      - Statements, 1948 (Box-folder 53: 7)
      - Topics for discussion (Box-folder 53: 8)
    - Universities Committee on post-war international problems (Box-folder 53: 9)
  - Summary chronology of developments in international relations (Box-folder 53: 10)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 53: 11)
  - Telephone list (Box-folder 53: 12)
  - United Nations Charter (Box-folder 53: 13-14)
    Includes articles, correspondence, memoranda, and holograph notes made by Charles Rothwell regarding estimate of pagination, final stages of the completion, and text certification of the printing of the Charter.
  - Workbook (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Working paper (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Writings (Box-folder 54: 3-5)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 55: 1)
- General Subject File, 1946-1979 (Box 55-61)
  Articles, brochures, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, handbook, information sheets, interview, manual, memoranda, notes, press release, printed matter, proceedings, projects, reports, speeches, study, surveys, telegrams, workbooks and writings relating to various countries and organizations, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Also includes records relating to Air War College and Naval War College, and materials about Alger Hiss, Secretary General, United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, California. See also: Stanford University and Hoover Institution series.
  - Air War College
    - General (Box-folder 55: 2)
    - Brochure (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 55: 4)
    - Instruction circular (Box-folder 55: 5)
    - Manual (Box-folder 55: 6)
    - Reading list (Box-folder 55: 7)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 55: 8)
  - Australia
    - General (Box-folder 55: 9)
    - Bulletin (Box-folder 55: 10)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 55: 11)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 55: 12)
    - Radio special project (Box-folder 55: 13)
    - Statements, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 55: 14)
  - Brookings Institution
    - General (Box-folder 55: 15)
    - Brochure (Box-folder 55: 16)
    - Correspondence
      - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 55: 17)
      - 1948 (Box-folder 55: 18)
      - 1949 (Box-folder 55: 19)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 55: 20)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 55: 21)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 55: 22)
    - Discussion materials (Box-folder 56: 1-3)
    - Information sheets (Box-folder 56: 4)
    - List of participants (Box-folder 56: 5)
    - Memoranda
      - Undated (Box-folder 56: 6)
      - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 56: 7)
    - Notes (Box-folder 56: 8)
    - Press releases (Box-folder 56: 9)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 56: 10)
    - Program (Box-folder 56: 11)
    - Projects (Box-folder 56: 12)
    - Reports, 1957 (Box-folder 56: 13)
    - Schedule (Box-folder 56: 14)
    - Seminars (Box-folder 56: 15)
    - Study (Box-folder 56: 16)
    - Workbook (Box-folder 56: 17)
    - Workbook (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - Canada
    - Article (Box-folder 57: 2)
    - Brochure (Box-folder 57: 3)
  - Caribbean, article (Box-folder 57: 4)
  - Chile, general (Box-folder 57: 5)
  - Europe
    - Clippings (Box-folder 57: 6)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box-folder 57: 7)
    - Journal (Box-folder 57: 8)
    - News bulletin (Box-folder 57: 9)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 57: 10)
  - Fiji, printed matter (Box-folder 57: 11)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Press releases (Box-folder 57: 12)
    - Speech, 1959 (Box-folder 57: 13)
  - Great Britain
    - Brochure (Box-folder 57: 14)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 57: 15)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 57: 16)
  - Greece, general (Box-folder 57: 17)
  - Hiss, Alger
    - Clippings (Box-folder 57: 18)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 57: 19)
    - Memorandum of conversation (Box-folder 57: 20)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 57: 21)
    - Transcript of a speech, 1946 (Box-folder 57: 22)